Nathaniel Reister

(646) 634-7800 | nathaniel.reister@gmail.com Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Led teams and contributed to projects that left lasting positive effects in our communities. Organized the workflow of large development projects in WA and NY. I possess an incessant determination to capitalize on opportunities for optimization and innovation. With a research and result driven perspective I bring success to my work.

SKILLS

Languages/Development: C#, Python, JavaScript, ¡Query, Ajax, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, APIs, Node.js

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite3

Frameworks: .NET, Django, React, Web Forms, Entity, Bootstrap4

Architectural Paradigms: Object Oriented Programming, MVC

Project Management: Agile/Scrum, Azure DevOps, Git/GitHub, Jira

IDEs Visual Studio 2019/Code, PyCharm

Soft Skills: Collaboration, leadership, coordination, communication, analysis,

creativity, adaptability.

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer | Freelance | Remote | December 2020 - Current

Skillset | C#, .NET, Razor, Entity Framework, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap 4, Agile/Scrum, Jira, Slack

Develop web applications using .Net Entity Framework Code First

Software Developer Intern | Prosper IT Consulting | Portland, OR | October 2020 - December 2020 - Skillset | C#, .NET, Razor, Entity Framework, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap 4, Agile/Scrum, Azure DevOps, Slack

 Develop a web application using. Net Entity framework Code First with product models integrated via relational database and scaffold to provide user manipulation. Completion of user requested changes to UI as well as locate and correct bugs.

Skillset | Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Agile/Scrum, Slack

- Development of front and back end components of a web application using Django that collected user preferences from search and survey results then provided suggestions.

Construction Superintendent | BMDC Services | Seattle, WA | June 2018 - Current

Orchestrate the development and construction of commercial and residential projects.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Certification | The Tech Academy | Portland, OR Graduated December 2020 Courses | C#, MVC, Python, Django, JavaScript/JQuery, SQL/TSQL(MS SQL Server), HTML5, CSS3, AJAX/XML, Source Control(Git & GitHub), Agile/Scrum Methodologies, OOP, fundamentals of computer technologies.

Bachelor of Arts | SUNY College At Brockport, Brockport, NY | Double Bachelors - Graduated MAY 2015 Communications | Mass Media, Interpersonal, Public, Persuasion tactics.

Political Science | Law and Legal Procedure, Constitutional Law, Comparative Politics.

Collegiate Achievement | Dean List with Honor | Cum Laude | Resident Asst. | Student Gov Chief Justice